We said already that snooping is only
one of the two ways to do coherence. The
other way is directory based coherence.
So let's first see why do we even want
directory based coherence. What's wrong
with snooping? In snooping we had to
broadcast all of the requests we make so
that others can see them and also to
establish ordering. For example, for
rights we need to establish the ordering
so that we can obey the third coherence
property. But that means that there
needs to be a single bus on which all of
the requests from all of the cores go
both cache misses and also coherence
requests that are just sending out
invalidations and so on. So the bus that
we were using for broadcast becomes a
bottleneck and as a result snooping does
not really work well if we have more
than something like 8 to 16 cores.
Beyond that point, most of the time the
cores are just spending waiting for the
bus to put requests on it. So really we
get no further benefit from additional
cores. So what we need to solve this
bottleneck is a nonbroadcast network
over which we're going to send our
requests so that many requests could be
going on at the same time. But then we
have the problems of how do we observe
those requests that we need to see. So
for example, if we are in a shared
state, it had better be that when there
is a right by somebody else, we observe
that right so that we can move to the
invalid state to avoid incoherence. And
also how do we decide what the ordering
is for requests that go to the same
block. So for example, how do we decide
what's the ordering between rights done
at different cores if these requests can
be made on different parts of the
network? And the structure that does
this is called a directory.